<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">

<channel>
  <title>Information Research Feed</title>
  <link>http://informationr.net/ir/contents.html</link>
  <description>An RSS feed to keep up to date with Information Research</description>
  <image>
  <url>http://informationr.net/ir/mini_logo.gif</url>
  <title>Information Research</title>
  <link>http://informationr.net</link>ß
</image>
  <item>
    <title>Editorial</title>
    <link>http://informationr.net/ir/19-2/editor192.html</link>
    <description>An introduction to the issue</description>
  </item>
  
    <item>
    <title>T.D. Wilson - The e-book phenomenon: a disruptive technology</title>
    <link>http://informationr.net/ir/19-2/paper612.html</link>
    <description>The e-book and its associated technology have emerged as a disruptive technology over the past ten years. The aim of this paper is to discuss some of the consequences of this development, based on the work of the e-books in Sweden research project.</description>
  </item>
  
      <item>
    <title>Zoran Velagić - The discourse on printed and electronic books: analogies, oppositions, and perspectives</title>
    <link>http://informationr.net/ir/19-2/paper619.html</link>
    <description>The point of departure for this paper is the twofold analogy (analogy of content, analogy of medium) between printed and electronic books, the aim being to draw attention to the usual perception of their capacities and relationships, to provide a rather detailed analysis of the outcome and sustainability of such analogies and ultimately to indicate the drawbacks involved.</description>
  </item>
  
      <item>
    <title>Annika Bergström and Lars Höglund - A national survey of early adopters of e-book reading in Sweden</title>
    <link>http://informationr.net/ir/19-2/paper621.html</link>
    <description>Reading literature is believed to be a cornerstone of democracy and good citizenship. With a decline in book reading and an increasing e-book market, it is of importance to follow the diffusion of e-book reading.</description>
  </item>
  
      <item>
    <title>Elena Maceviciute, Martin Borg, Ramune Kuzminiene and Katie Konrad - The acquisition of e-books in the libraries of Swedish higher education institutions</title>
    <link>http://informationr.net/ir/19-2/paper620.html</link>
    <description> Our aim is to compare the advantages and problems of e-book acquisition identified in research literature to those experienced by two Swedish university libraries.</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
  <title>Anabel Quan-Haase, Kim Martin and Kathleen Schreurs - Not all on the same page: e-book adoption and technology exploration by seniors</title>
  <link>http://informationr.net/ir/19-2/paper622.html</link>
  <description>This paper aims to understand the adoption of e-books and e-readers by persons aged sixty and above. This includes an investigation into where seniors are in the stages of e-book adoption.</description>
  </item>
  
    <item>
  <title>Hazel C. Engelsmann, Elke Greifeneder, Nikoline D. Lauridsen and Anja G. Nielsen - Validation of the visitor and resident framework in an e-book setting</title>
  <link>http://informationr.net/ir/19-2/paper623.html</link>
  <description>By applying the visitor and resident framework on e-book usage, the article explores whether the concepts of a resident and a visitor can help to explain e-book use, and can help to gain a better insight into users' motivations for e-book use.</description>
  </item>
  
     <item>
  <title>Ji Hei Kang and Nancy Everhart - Digital textbooks: school librarians' stages of concerns in initial implementation</title>
  <link>http://informationr.net/ir/19-2/paper625.html</link>
  <description>This research focuses on determining the levels of concern that librarians from kindergarten through grade 12 (K-12) have regarding digital textbooks, and does so by applying the concerns based adoption model. </description>
  </item>

	
	    <item>
  <title>Adam Girard - Reader's block: a systematic review of barriers to adoption, access and use in e-book user studies. </title>
  <link>http://informationr.net/ir/19-2/paper624.html</link>
  <description>Electronic books have been the focus of much research in information science and library studies. As the availability and variety of portable reading devices, channels for access, business models, and file formats increase, they present readers with many choices when accessing and using their reading materials. Readers also have to make a vast array of other considerations such as, where to read, what type of content is suitable to read electronically, and social and cultural impacts on reading practice. A number of studies have described criteria of these complex intersections between devices, content, behaviour, and the settings in which they occur as opportunities and barriers that facilitate or prohibit adoption, access, and use of e-books by the reader.</description>
    </item>
	
	  
    <item>
  <title>Pere Masip - Impact of assessment criteria on publication behaviour. The case of communication research in Spain</title>
  <link>http://informationr.net/ir/19-2/paper613.html</link>
  <description>This paper outlines the evolution of Spanish production in the area of communication research over the last seventeen years. It analyses whether the consolidation of the existing systems of assessment of scientific activity have been mirrored by an increase in the output of Spanish authors in journals indexed by the Social Sciences Citation Index</description>
  </item>
  
    <item>
  <title>Pamela J. McKenzie, Elisabeth Davies and Sherilyn Williams - Information creation and the ideological code of managerialism in the work of keeping track</title>
  <link>http://informationr.net/ir/19-2/paper614.html</link>
  <description>This paper contributes to our understanding of the little-studied practices of information creation by studying the work of keeping track, e.g., by creating lists and calendars. We analyse the work of keeping track in terms of Smith's concept of the ideological code and argue that a managerial imperative pervades this work, even in domestic contexts.</description>
  </item>
  
    <item>
  <title>M. Asim Qayyum and Kirsty Williamson - The online information experiences of news-seeking young adults</title>
  <link>http://informationr.net/ir/19-2/paper615.html</link>
  <description>Based on the premise that news of all kinds is a form of information, the purpose of this study was to understand use of news sources by young adults in fast-paced and dynamic online media environments.</description>
  </item>
  
      <item>
  <title>M. Asim Qayyum, Kim M. Thompson, Mary Anne Kennan and Annemaree Lloyd - The provision and sharing of information between service providers and settling refugees</title>
  <link>http://informationr.net/ir/19-2/paper616.html</link>
  <description>The purpose of this study is to understand the provision and sharing of information between service providers and settling refugees while refugees transit to new living environments. Efforts of service providers are investigated to understand if community participation is enabled, social exclusion reduced, and barriers to information access and use minimized.</description>
  </item>
  
        <item>
  <title>Patricia M. Alexander and Emile Silvis - Towards extending actor-network theory with a graphical syntax for information systems research</title>
  <link>http://informationr.net/ir/19-2/paper617.html</link>
  <description>This study argues that the utility of actor-network theory as a conceptual tool for information systems research can be increased by expressing actor-network theory in a graphical format. To this end, a graphical syntax was designed based on a comprehensive conceptualisation of actor-network theory. </description>
  </item>
  
        <item>
  <title>Diane H. Sonnenwald, Hanna Maurin Söderholm, Gregory F. Welch, Bruce A. Cairns, James E. Manning and Henry Fuchs - Illuminating collaboration in emergency health care situations: paramedic-physician collaboration and 3D telepresence technology</title>
  <link>http://informationr.net/ir/19-2/paper618.html</link>
  <description>This paper focuses on paramedics' perspectives regarding paramedic-physician collaboration today, and their perspectives regarding the potential of 3D telepresence technology in the future. </description>
  </item>
  
  
      <item>
  <title>Book reviews</title>
  <link>http://informationr.net/ir/reviews/reviews.html</link>
  <description>Eight new books are reviewed in this issue</description>
  </item>
   </channel>
 </rss>



